

Lydia she/her 28.09.1995 $Youngblood \\ \begin{tabular}{ll} Iydia.youngblood \\ 4.github.io \\ \end{tabular}$

ABOUT ME

I'm a curious and pragmatic cartographer with a social and environmental geography background. I have experience in geodata visualization and research, cartographic design, GIS, qualitative surveying, customer service, and intercultural communication.

My other interests include bouldering, hiking, dancing, analog photography, and knitting.

PUBLICATIONS

Youngblood, L. and Gartner, G.: Narrating the route: route memorability in navigation instructions augmented with narrative, Abstr. Int. Cartogr. Assoc., 5, 94, https://doi.org/ 10.5194/ica-abs-5-94-2022. 2022.

LANGUAGES

English German Spanish Italian •••000

SKILLS

- ArcGIS Pro, AGOL, QGIS
- Python, R, Java, HTML, CSS, SQL
- Affinity and Adobe design products
- Survey123
- Tableau
- Postgres, PostGIS
- Print mapping
- Mobile interface and web design
- Navigation system design
- Data preparation
- Project management
- Time management

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Cartography

2022

Technische Universtät München, Technische Universtät Wien, Technische Universtät Dresden, University of Twente

Grade: 1,1 (highest distinction)

- Thesis at TU Wien: Narrating the route: Route memorability in navigation instructions augmented with narrative
- Courses in cartographic design, location based services, GIS, web mapping, mobile cartography, geodatabases, geostatistics, remote sensing
- German Academic Exchange Service (DAAD) scholar

Bachelor of Arts in Geography

2017

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill

Grade: 3.9 (highest distinction, DE = 1,1)

- Second major in Global Studies (concentrations: Latin America, Health & Environment)
- Minor in Hispanic Studies
- Honors Carolina, Phi Beta Kappa, 5x Dean's list recipient

Pontificia Universidad Católica de Perú, semester exchange

2016

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Esri Deutschland Konferenz Volunteer

2020

Esri, Bonn, Germany

Supported ESRI staff during the 2020 ESRI conference in Bonn. Attended lectures, workshops, and networking events to remain up-to-date with current cartographic practices

Administrative Assistant

2019-2020

BrauHotel Bonn & Bar Balthasar, Bonn, Germany

- Provided office support in a hotel and bar to improve German. Tasks included checking in, charging, and communicating with guests, event planning, preparing hotel for check-ins, serving guests, and stocking
- Responsible for redesigning the 300+ item menu and social media posts for promotions and events
- Developed and implemented a filing system for all invoices, receipts, and orders for the bar and hotel

Student Assistant

2017

Esri User Conference, San Diego, CA, USA

- Selected to be one of 60 Student Assistants out of 1,700 applicants
- Facilitated smooth operation of a conference for 18,000+ participants by providing support for Esri staff, including monitoring technical workshops and registering and assisting participants
- Gained exposure to new GIS applications in imaging, design, and analysis

Contract GIS Specialist

2016

RTI, Durham, NC, USA

- Identified and categorized residential and non-residential sampling units in ArcGIS based on aerial imagery in rural and urban Nigeria for projects aimed at increasing success and response rates for on-the-ground survey teams
- Assisted with quality control on time-sensitive projects















OTHER EXPERIENCE

Lead Barista 2018-2019

Friends Café, Chapel Hill, NC, USA

- Prepared detailed espresso drinks in a specialty coffee shop with high attention to detail and customer satisfaction.
- Remedied both café and customer mistakes in a professional manner
- Promoted to Lead Barista within 6 weeks based on efficiency, attention to detail, and skill.

House Manager | Assistant House Manager | Usher | Administrative Assistant

Carolina Performing Arts, Chapel Hill, NC, USA

- Managed 25 student-staff members for world-class performances at Memorial Hall, including Yo-Yo Ma, Youssou N'Dour, and Buddy Guy
- Responsible for presenting efficient and polished service to every patron, on both individual and small scales

2013-2017

- Directed front-of-house, audience interactions, and ensured that patrons had a safe and enjoyable experience
- Managed 20-person student staff on pre-performance tasks, ensuring a smooth and on-time start of performance
- Took initiative on most issues but comfortably requested assistance if necessary

SELECTED PROJECTS

- Kenan's climb: Honoring Alexander Kenan's record hike
- Can you see clearly now? Monitoring the effects of air quality in India during the COVID-19 lockdown"
- Investment? Mapping potential inundation of the Waldrop family cottage
- Policing Day Labor in the United States: A Case Study in Carrboro, North Carolina
- Chagas Disease: Key transmission factors in Latin America are not useful in assessing transmission risk in the United States
- Changes in veteran population: A look at three North Carolina communities
- Killer Soy: How agricultural practices have transformed the children around the fields in Córdoba, Argentina (2015)

ADDITIONAL COURSES

HarvardX Data Science: R Basics, Visualization

Esri: Earth Imagery at Work, DIY Geo-Apps, Cartography

GEONATURA: Applied Geomatics to Social and Environmental Issues

VOLUNTEERING

Durham Housing Authority (2020): Volunteered with DHA to assist with acute needs of seniors in my community during the COVID-19 pandemic

Orange County Literacy (2018-19): Tutored an adult student working towards their G.E.D.

Carrboro Community Garden (2018-19): Worked in the garden to meet neighbors UNC Study Abroad Office (2017): Ambassador for university study abroad program